export const COSTINGA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Cost Accounting involves",
A: "assessment of annual turnover",
B: "collection and analysis of expenditure",
C: "determination of staff satisfaction",
D: "determination of annual profits",
answer: "B. collection and analysis of expenditure",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The classification and recording of monetary transaction is, the function of",
A: "cost accounting",
B: "financial accounting",
C: "management accounting",
D: "stores accounting",
answer: "B. financial accounting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The objective of cost classification is to",
A: "analyse costs for control purposes",
B: "compute the total cost of production",
C: "determine the elements of cost",
D: "determine the expired portion of cost",
answer: "A.  analyse costs for control purposes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Classification of cost into fixed and variable cost is classification by",
A: "behaviour",
B: "controllability",
C: "function",
D: "nature",
answer: "A.  behaviour",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The cost of turning raw materials into finished goods is",
A: "conversion cost",
B: "prime cost",
C: "production cost",
D: "total cost",
answer: "A.  conversion cost",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The elements of cost are",
A: "direct cost and indirect cost",
B: "fixed and variable cost",
C: "materials, labour and expenses",
D: "prime cost, conversion cost and overheads",
answer: "C. materials, labour and expenses",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The objective of periodic stocktaking is to",
A: "ascertain the physical quantities of a material",
B: "avoid disruption in the production or sales",
C: "check a proportion of stock daily",
D: "show the stock balance after every stock movement",
answer: "A.  ascertain the physical quantities of a material",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following methods of pricing stock issues results in low closing stock values in times of rising prices?",
A: "FIFO",
B: "LIFO",
C: "Simple average",
D: "Weighted average",
answer: "B. LIFO",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The request by a firm to a supplier to supply goods is made by a",
A: "goods received note",
B: "material requisition",
C: "purchases order",
D: "purchase requisition",
answer: "C. purchases order",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Bin card is attached to the actual materials and it shows",
A: "date and value of stock",
B: "physical movement of stock",
C: "quantity and value of stock",
D: "value of stock at anytime",
answer: "B. physical movement of stock",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Cost of stock issued using FlFO is",
A: "GH¢2,550",
B: "GH¢2,450",
C: "GH¢2,350",
D: "GH¢2,250",
answer: "B. GH¢2,450",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Cost of stock issued using Simple Average is",
A: "GH¢2,550",
B: "GH¢2,400",
C: "GH¢2,350",
D: "GH¢2,250",
answer: "B. GH¢2,400",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. What is the value of closing stock using LIFO?",
A: "GH¢2,550",
B: "GH¢2,450",
C: "GH¢2,350",
D: "GH¢2,250",
answer: "A.  GH¢2,550",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The portion of an employee’s earnings that is treated as an overhead is",
A: "basic salary",
B: "net pay",
C: "overtime premium",
D: "taxable pay",
answer: "C. overtime premium",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Incentive schemes are effective when",
A: "all workers earn the same amount",
B: "skilled workers earn more than unskilled workers",
C: "there is no artificial limit to earnings",
D: "unskilled workers earn more than skilled workers",
answer: "C. there is no artificial limit to earnings",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Wages for Counter is",
A: "D36,800",
B: "D28,800",
C: "D20,000",
D: "D16,800",
answer: "A.  D36,800",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Guaranteed wages for Diablo is",
A: "D36,800",
B: "D28,800",
C: "D20,000",
D: "D16,800",
answer: "C.  D20,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Wages for Diablo is",
A: "D36,800",
B: "D28,800",
C: "D20 ,000",
D: "D16,800",
answer: "B.  D28,800",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The total of indirect cost is",
A: "expenditure",
B: "fixed cost",
C: "overhead",
D: "variable cost",
answer: "C. overhead",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Overheads are added to product cost by",
A: "absorption",
B: "allocation",
C: "apportionment",
D: "distribution",
answer: "A.  absorption",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. When actual overhead is less than overhead absorbed, overhead is",
A: "completely absorbed",
B: "over absorbed",
C: "over apportioned",
D: "under absorbed",
answer: "D.  under absorbed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Costs that are not directly traceable to a product are",
A: "controllable cost",
B: "overheads",
C: "sunk cost",
D: "variable cost",
answer: "B. overheads",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Overheads absorbed into the cost of production are",
A: "actual overheads",
B: "over absorbed overheads",
C: "pre-determined overheads",
D: "under absorbed overheads",
answer: "C. pre-determined overheads",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A suitable cost unit for the transport industry is",
A: "cost of fuel per day",
B: "cost per kilometre",
C: "cost per vehicle",
D: "cost per passenger per kilometre",
answer: "D. cost per passenger per kilometre",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. In which of the following industries will service costing be used?",
A: "Construction",
B: "Furniture manufacturing",
C: "Hospitality",
D: "Petrol refinery",
answer: "C. Hospitality",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In process costing, the output of one process becomes",
A: "input of the next process",
B: "input of the previous process",
C: "output of the next process",
D: "output of the previous process",
answer: "A.  input of the next process",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The job cost sheet shows",
A: "labour cost for the job",
B: "material cost for the job",
C: "time spent on the job",
D: "selling price of the job",
answer: "D. selling price of the job",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. By-products are",
A: "incidental products",
B: "losses in process costing",
C: "spoilage in process costing",
D: "waste products",
answer: "A.  incidental products",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The part of cost of completed contract held against possible defective work is",
A: "apparent profit",
B: "buffer funds",
C: "surplus funds",
D: "retention money",
answer: "D. retention money",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The selling price of a job is usually determined on the basis of",
A: "cost plus percentage",
B: "pre-determine prices",
C: "standard pricing",
D: "transfer pricing",
answer: "A.  cost plus percentage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Batch costing is used where production involves",
A: "different job specifications",
B: "production at customer’s premises",
C: "several units of an identical product",
D: "two or more contracts",
answer: "C. several units of an identical product",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The technique of costing that distinguishes between fixed cost and variable cost is",
A: "absorption costing",
B: "marginal costing",
C: "standard costing",
D: "total costing",
answer: "B. marginal costing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Fixed cost is",
A: "Le50,000",
B: "Le487,500",
C: "Le325,000",
D: "Le162,500",
answer: "D. Le162,500",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Selling price per unit is",
A: "Le125",
B: "Le100",
C: "Le75",
D: "Le25",
answer: "B. Le100",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Total contribution at break-even point is",
A: "Le650,000",
B: "Le487,500",
C: "Le325,000",
D: "Le162,500",
answer: "D. Le162,500",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Marginal costing technique is used for",
A: "cash budgeting",
B: "contract costing",
C: "employee management",
D: "planning and decision making",
answer: "D. planning and decision making",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A budget must be related to",
A: "a long period of time",
B: "a short period of time",
C: "no period of time",
D: "specific period of time",
answer: "D. specific period of time",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The production budget depends on",
A: "cash budget",
B: "material usage budget",
C: "purchase forecast",
D: "sales forecast",
answer: "D. sales forecast",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A budget is a",
A: "forecast activity for a period",
B: "quantitative expression of a plan",
C: "total cost incurred for a period",
D: "total production for a period",
answer: "B. quantitative expression of a plan",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. An advantage of standard costing is that it",
A: "concentrates on cost only",
B: "measures both profit and loss",
C: "motivates employees",
D: "reduces cost of operation",
answer: "C. motivates employees",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Material cost variance is divided into",
A: "price and efficiency variance",
B: "price and usage variances",
C: "rate and efficiency variances",
D: "rate and usage variances",
answer: "B. price and usage variances",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. An ideal standard assumes",
A: "continuous operating conditions",
B: "current operating conditions",
C: "efficient operating conditions",
D: "perfect operating conditions",
answer: "D. perfect operating conditions",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Standard cost is",
A: "a fixed cost",
B: "an actual cost",
C: "a pre-determined cost",
D: "a period cost",
answer: "C. a pre-determined cost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following items appear in financial accounts but not in cost accounts?",
A: "Dividend received",
B: "Sales of finished goods",
C: "Wages and salaries",
D: "transfers from stores to production",
answer: "A.  Dividend received",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The difference between cost and financial accounts profits is caused by",
A: "different stock valuation",
B: "purchase of raw materials",
C: "sales of goods",
D: "wages of factory workers",
answer: "A.  different stock valuation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The objective of Cost Ledger Control Accounts is to",
A: "complete double entry in Cost Accounts",
B: "complete Profit and Loss Account",
C: "record cost of processing raw material",
D: "record purchases of raw material",
answer: "A.  complete double entry in Cost Accounts",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The system of accounting that separates financial and cost accounts is",
A: "double entry accounting",
B: "integrated accounts",
C: "interlocking account",
D: "single entry accounting",
answer: "C. interlocking account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]